#### Jordi Juan Iveson

jordijuaniveson@gmail.com | 07879 688042

Recent engineering master's graduate with strong analytical and problem-solving ability. I started coding during my MSc for data quality improvements and have continued my interest over this last 5 months, completing much of Codecademy's front-end course (www.codecademy.com). I also have a public GitHub account presenting some of my HTML, JavaScript, and React work and also my algorithmic problem-solving interest using Python.

Please see: https://jjiveson.github.io/PortfolioWebsite/index.html

#### Education

### Mar 2021 - Present: Codecademy Full Stack Developer Course (www.codecademy.com)

I have interests in React, JavaScript, HTML and rapid development of complex algorithms using Python whilst maintaining well-structured and clean code. Please see my GitHub portfolio. During the course, I have completed the following projects and coding challenges:

- React-based project using Spotify API calls to manage user playlists
- Portfolio website using JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- NodeJS and JavaScript maze project
- Python coding challenge problems
- Company website for sabosoap.com using HTML, CSS
- Other smaller projects using JavaScript and HTML (number guesser, credit card validation)

#### **Modules Currently Completed:**

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux and Python.

The course provides a good grounding in these technologies and provides many opportunities for their practical application with coding challenges and assessed projects throughout.

## Modules in progress:

PHP, SQL (including complex queries and schema design), GIT.

The completed modules provide me with core knowledge of the LAMP stack (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Python, SQL). The course also includes future modules in Java and C#, languages I am keen to learn as part of my CPD.

# Sep 2019 – Dec 2020: MSc Energy and Environmental Management | University of Twente | Distinction

Thesis Title: Assessing the biomass potential for supplying an increased blending mandate in Argentina with a focus on food security. [Grade - 85%]

Using the BEFS RA framework (designed by the Food and Agriculture Organisation), I performed a detailed assessment of the potential for increasing biofuel production in Argentina in line with existing governmental policy. The study involved an assessment of the country context, data collection and analysis of the energy and agriculture sector, calculation of feedstock potential and an economic feasibility assessment of potential changes to policy.

## Skills developed

 Data cleansing and cleaning using Python prior to uploading into FAO's excel spreadsheet.

- Demonstrated rapid progress and learning in new fields with minimal supervision including energy and water management.
- Developed knowledge relating to national energy policy, sustainability law and energy audits, and certification.
- Strong communication skills, both written and verbal, developed through presentations and report writing.

# Sep 2014 – Aug 2018: BEng (Hons) Chemical Engineering | Swansea University | 2:2 Skills developed

- Developed understanding of broad engineering concepts, including thermodynamics and fluid mechanics, chemical processes, including process modelling and reactor design, and collection and analysis of data relating to process equipment in lab work.
- Project design skills relating to the design of a polycarbonate process plant as part of
  the final year group design project. Working in a team of five, the study consisted of
  chemical process selection, energy and mass balance calculations, reactor selection
  and design, economic appraisal and costing, process safety and environmental
  assessment.
- Developed skills relating to delivering a specified project with a team, problem solving and analytical thinking.
- Introduction to MATLAB, Aspen Plus and UniSim software.

# Sep 2012 - Aug 2014: A Levels | Sackville Sixth Form, East Grinstead

Spanish (A), Mathematics (B), Chemistry (C), Further Mathematics (D), AS Physics (C).

## Sep 2010 - Aug 2012: GCSE's | Sackville School, East Grinstead

3 grade A\*, 6 grade A (including Maths and English), 2 grade B.

## Work experience

#### Jan 2020 – Mar 2020 Market Data Intern | Ted Data Solutions Ltd

Responsible for sourcing, cleaning, and formatting data of the IT UK job market. I used Python to collate and transform the json data into a standard csv format for upload and analysis of trends using Excel. Intern remote work that required time-management and proactiveness.

## Oct 2018 – May 2019: Barista | Malabar Coffee House, Sevenoaks

Furthered my skills in communication and working closely as part of a small team and gained an understanding of how small businesses work. Responsibilities included opening and closing the shops, stock management, operating and cashing up the till and doing the daily banking.

## Jul 2017 – Aug 2018: Summer Placement | Integrated Water Services, Walsall

Summer placement at IWS, a subsidiary of South Staffs Water PLC. On the placement I worked in a variety of departments and was able to gain an overview of the whole process of acquiring and completing water projects to supply drinking water. My placement at IWS provided me with a broad grounding in and understanding of how professional industry works, specifically the water industry.

## June 2016 - September 2016: Kitchen Staff | The Ounce and Ivy, Wetherspoon's East Grinstead

Developed good communication skills, as well as the ability to work under pressure and maintain a high quality of service whilst meeting strict deadlines for orders. Responsibilities included opening the kitchen and running the breakfast and lunch service, quality control and ensuring cleanliness and health and safety standards were upheld.

## Jul 2015 – Sep 2015: Bar Staff | The Flying Horse, Wetherspoon's Gatwick

Developed strong customer service skills, teamwork, working effectively during busy periods to ensure fast turnover of customers. Responsibilities included operating the till and dealing with customer satisfaction.

## Apr 2013 – Sep 2014: Shop Floor Assistant | Homebase, East Grinstead

Public-facing role that enabled me to developed customer service skills, as well as time keeping and organisation skills relating to stock rotation. Role involved organising and managing garden section, pricing and stock reduction and assisting customers with orders and with complaints and queries.

**Interests and Hobbies:** Scuba diving, Radio/Music, Art. **Languages:** Trilingual (fluent English, Spanish, and Catalan).

**References:** Available on request.